Register to The Thomas de Hartmann Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Transcriptions of Music by Other Composers, I.I
    - [Chant populaire, arr.], Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 2 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 180)
      Transcribed for cello by Thomas de Hartmann.
    - [Chant populaire, arr.], Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 2 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - [Khovantstchina. Persian dance, arr.] Danse des persanes / M. Moussorgsky. -- Paris: Bessel, 1949., Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; 1 score (11 p.) + 1 part (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 181)
      Plate no: W. 8401 B
    - [Khovantstchina. Persian dance, arr.] Danses des persanes, Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; 1 score (10 p.) + 1 part (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 181)
      Transcription for cello and piano by Thomas de Hartmann.
    - [Khovantschina. Martha's song, arr.] Cantabile / M. Moussorgsky. -- Paris: Bessel, 1949., Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; 1 score (3 p.) + 1 part (1 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 181)
      Plate no: W. 8402 B
    - [Khovantschina. Martha's song, arr.] Cantabile d'après un air de Moussorgsky., Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; 1 score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 20, Folder 181)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, I.J
    - [Sketches], 11 p. of music in 2 quires. (Box 21, Folder 182)
      Unidentified.
    - [Sketches], 19 p. of music in 2 quires. (Box 21, Folder 183)
    - [Sketches], 29 p. of music in 2 quires. (Box 21, Folder 184)
      Quire 2: possibly for Concierto Andaluz for flute and orchestra.
      See: box 6, folder 39.
    - [Sketches], 2 p. of music in 1 quire. (Box 21, Folder 185)
    - [Sketches], 10 p. of music in 1 quire. (Box 21, Folder 186)
  - Sketchbooks, I.K
    - [Sketchbook 1], 47 p. of holograph sketches; 11 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 187)
      Sketch titles: Concertino pour saxo, Symphonie.
    - [Sketchbook 2], 64 p. of holograph sketches; 11 x 16 cm. (Box 21, Folder 187)
    - [Sketchbook 3], 49 p. of holograph sketches; 10 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 187)
      Sketch titles: Ausonius[?], Concerto Saint-Saens, Concerto Schumann.
    - [Sketchbook 4], 3 p. of holograph sketches; 10 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 188)
    - [Sketchbook 5], 14 p. of holograph sketches; 10 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 188)
      Sketch title: Tramuntana.
    - [Sketchbook 6], 3 p. of holograph sketches; 10 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 188)
    - [Sketchbook 7], 5 p. of holograph sketches; 9 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 189)
      34 p. of manuscript notes.
    - [Sketchbook 8], 36 p. of holograph sketches; 8 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 189)
    - [Sketchbook 9], 5 p. of holograph sketches; 8 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 190)
    - [Sketchbook 10], 22 p. of holograph sketches; 7 x 13 cm. (Box 21, Folder 190)
    - [Sketchbook 11], 17 p. of holograph sketches; 18 x 14 cm. (Box 21, Folder 190)
      Inside cover transliterated: Konspektch probshchich kontrapunkta strogalo stshchich.
    - [Sketchbook 12], 30 p. of manuscript; 17 x 27 cm. (Box 21, Folder 191)
      Contents: themes from Beethoven symphonies.
- Auxiliary Material for Stage Works, Series II
  - Material relating to Der Gelbe Klang, II.A
    For music see: Gelbe Klang (sketches) Box 4, Folder 37
    - Scenarios, II.A.1
      - [Gelbe Klang] Der Gelbe Klang / Wassily Kandinsky. -- Munich, 1912., 19 p.; 29 cm. (Box 22, Folder 192)
        In Dem Blauen Reiter.
        Typescript, annotations in pencil.
        Original with 1 photocopy.
      - [Gelbe Klang] The yellow sound., 24 p.; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 193)
        Typescript in English.
        Translator unidentified.
        Original with 2 photocopies.
      - [Gelbe Klang] The yellow sound., 17 p.; 27 cm. (Box 22, Folder 194)
        4 copies.
        Copy #4 incomplete, lacks final page.
      - [Gelbe Klang], 11 p.; 22 x 36 cm. (Box 22, Folder 195)
        Manuscript in English.
        Possibly by Thomas de Hartmann.
      - [Gelbe Klang], 14 p.; 28 cm. (Box 22, Folder 195)
        Manuscript in German, English, and Russian.
      - [Gelbe Klang] The yellow sound, a stage-composition by Kandinsky., 22 p.; 28 cm. (Box 22, Folder 195)
      - [Gelbe Klang], 7 p.; 27 cm. (Box 22, Folder 196)
        Manuscript in Russian.
      - [Gelbe Klang] The yellow sound., 24 p.; 28 cm. (Box 22, Folder 196)
        Miscellaneous incomplete copies.
      - [Gelbe Klang], 1 p.; 23 cm. (Box 22, Folder 196)
        Time markings probably for music.
      - [Gelbe Klang], 2 p.; 16 cm. (Box 22, Folder 196)
        Photograph of note.
      - [Gelbe Klang], 1 p.; 22 cm. (Box 22, Folder 196)
    - Programs from 1982 performance, II.A.2
      - [Gelbe Klang] The yellow sound / Wassily Kandinsky, text; Thomas de Hartmann, music; Gunther Schuller, arranger and orchestrator; Ian Strasfogel, theatrical realization., 12 p. + 1 p. insert; 23 cm. (Box 22, Folder 197)
        Presented by the Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum.
        Marymount Manhattan Theatre, New York, NY.
        Feb. 9-14, 1982.
        5 copies.
    - Clippings, articles, and reviews, II.A.3
      - 1972 May 20, 1 item (Box 22, Folder 198)
      - 1982 [English], 13 items (Box 22, Folder 198)
      - 1982 [German], 7 items (Box 22, Folder 198)
    - Miscellaneous items, II.A.4
      - Ticket order form for Guggenheim production of Der Gelbe Klang., 2 items (Box 22, Folder 199)
      - Taken from G. Münter's book, p. 91., 3 p.; 27 cm. - 1 item (Box 22, Folder 199)
        Manuscript in German.
        Gelbe Klang mentioned on p. 2.
  - Works other than Der Gelbe Klang - Librettos and Scenarios, II.B
    - [Babette, op. 49], 1 libretto (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 200)
      Typescript.
    - [Babette, op. 49], 1 libretto (9 p.); 27 cm. (Box 23, Folder 200)
      Manuscript in ink.
    - [Babette, op. 49], 1 libretto (9 p.); 26 cm. (Box 23, Folder 200)
    - [Fête de la patronne] La fête de la patronne., 1 scenario (6 p.); 27 cm. (Box 23, Folder 200)
      Adaptation for television.
      On cover: Watercolor painting
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and majic [sic] (a bergerette of the 17th cen.), 1 libretto (5 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and majic [sic], 1 libretto (5 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and of majic [sic], 1 libretto (6 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and sorcery., 1 libretto (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie], 1 libretto (5 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie], 1 libretto (8 p.); 27 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
      With separate part for narrator [2 copies]
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie], 3 incomplete librettos (6 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and sorcery., 1 scenario (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 202)
      Annotations in red pen, 1 copy only.
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and sorcery., 1 scenario (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 202)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie] The forces of love and sorcery., 1 scenario (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 23, Folder 202)
    - [Général Boulanger] Le Général Boulanger. / Maurice Rostand. -- Paris, 1931., 1 play (50 p.); 30 cm. (Box 23, Folder 203)
      Play from which the libretto of unfinished opera was taken.
      (In La Petite Illustration)
      Inside cover: adaption musicale par Henri Cain.
    - [Général Boulanger], 1 libretto (4 p.); 20 to 32 cm. (Box 23, Folder 203)
      Incomplete fragments.
- Correspondence, III
  - Draft of letters to: Ansermet, Hawkes, Koussevitzky, Rodzinski, Vercambe, 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 204)
  - Académie Nationale de Musique et de Danse, 1935 Oct. 24; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
    Typescript letter signed to Henri Cain
  - Alexandrovsky, 1953-1954; 4 items. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Ancel, 1934-1935; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Ansermet, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 205)
    See: Draft of letters: Box 24, Folder 204
  - Arbell, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Association Artistique des Concerts Colonne, 1934 Mar. 9; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Balmont, K., 1934 June 12; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Belaieff, M.P.; publisher, 1932-1934; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Berglund, 1974 Oct. 12; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Bigot, Eugene, 1933-1934; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Bloch, Alfred, 1935 Oct. 9; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Blum, René, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Bookhout-Markovich, Sharon, 1974 Feb. 22; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Boult, Sir Adrian, 1935 Feb. 28; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Bunina, Vera N., n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Cain, Henri and Julia, 1933-1935; 30 items. (Box 24, Folder 206)
  - Cain, Henri, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 207)
    Autograph letter signed to Cefail
  - Cefail, 1934-1936; 4 items. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Cefail, 1934; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 207)
    Autograph letter signed to Henri Cain
  - Chamie, Nicolas, 1954 Jan. 17; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Chekov, Mikhail A., 1954; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Crosby, John, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Del Tredici, Robert, 1974; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Denison, J. K., 1937 June 30; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Dickinson, Niela, 1973 May 15; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - École Nationale des Langues Orientales Vivantes, 1933 Apr. 1; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Evreinow, S.A., 1953-1954; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Fenoult, 1937 Apr. 15; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Fokine, Michael and Vera, 1934; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Forsyth, J. A., 1934 May 19; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Genauer, 1972 Apr. 5; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Glazunov, Alexander, 1935; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Grohmann, Will, 1957; 6 items. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Grunebaum-Balluj, J., 1933 Dec. 13; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Gurdjieff, Georgi Ivanovitch, n.d.; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Hahl, Jelena, 1972-1976; 10 items. (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Harten, Georg, 1954 May 6; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Hartmann, Olga de, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 209)
    Autograph letter signed to Thomas de Hartmann
  - Hawkes, Ralph, 19-- Feb. 9; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 209)
    See also: Draft of letters: Box 24, Folder 204
  - Hekking, L. G., 1924 May 24; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Hogg, Ima, 1955 Nov. 11; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Kachie, S. Poladian, 1969; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Kaldor, Marcia, 1974 Oct. 16; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Kandinsky, Nina, 1934-1950; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 210)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1933-1935; 21 items. (Box 24, Folder 210)
  - Karr, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Ketchum, Charles, 1975; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Kirschke, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Kokouska, A., n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Koussevitzky, Serge, n.d.; * items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Lawton, Ralph, 1933 Dec. 17; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Leschetizky, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Lewiston, David, 1955; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Maklakov, V. A., 1934 Jan. 18; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
    Immigration official
  - Medtner, Nicolai, 1934; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Morant, E. S., 1934; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Nice Opéra, 1935; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Nicolaevitch, Andrei, 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Pohl, Vladimir, n.d.; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Popineau, 1935 Apr. 17; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Rebay, Hillay, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Rodzinski, n.d.; * items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Roethal, Hans K., 1972; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Rosenman, A., 1934 June 6; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Rostand, Maurice, 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Sanin, Alexander A., 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Sergeev, N., 1934; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Shoumatoff, 1918 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Smith, Mary, 1975 Aug. 24; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Smith, Mary, 1975 Jul. 28; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
    Typescript letter signed to William Segal
  - Sonsogno, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Stoll, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Strimer, O., 1934; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Swet, Gershon, 1954 Sep. 28; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Tcherepnin, Marie, 1933; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Théâtre National de l'Opéra Comique, 1934 May 7; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
    Autograph letter signed to Meitre
  - Trotsky, Ilya M., 1954; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Vercambe, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Weingartner, Felix, 1933 Dec. 15; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - White, Adolph, 1974; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Wood, Henry, 1934; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Yavlensky, 1933-1934; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Unidentified, 1933-1935; 38 items. (Box 24, Folder 213)
  - Notebook with manuscript, n.d.; 1 item; 16 p.; 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 214)
    Unidentified drafts of letters in Russian and English.
- Literary writings by de Hartmann, Series IV
  - About Kandinsky / Thomas de Hartmann. -- n.d., 9 copies, 4 to 6 p. each; 28 cm. (Box 24, Folder 215)
    Typescript in English with manuscript corrections.
  - About Kandinsky / Thomas de Hartmann. -- n.d., 16 p.; 28 cm. (Box 24, Folder 216)
    Typescript in English with manuscript corrections, 1 copy only.
  - Anarchy in the music / Thomas de Hartmann. -- n.d., 9 p.; 28 cm. (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - My remembrances of Sergei Ivanovich Tanieff / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Dec 4, 1956., 1 p.; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 24, Folder 218)
    Typescript in Russian.
    In La Pensée Russe.
    2 photocopies.
  - Notre vie avec Gurdjieff / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Paris: Planète, 1968., 229 p.; 21 cm. (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Our life with Mr. Gurdjieff / Thomas de Hartmann. -- New York: Cooper Square, 1964., xiii, 130 p.; 24 cm. (Box 25, Folder 220)
  - Our life with Mr. Gurdjieff / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Baltimore: Penguin, 1972., ix, 134 p.,; 18 cm. (Box 25, Folder 221)
  - Sergei Ivanovitch Tanieff / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Liverpool, 1956., p. 8-15; 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 222)
    In Tempo, vol. 39.
  - Über anarchie in der musik / Thomas de Hartmann. - n.d., 5 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 223)
    Typescript in German.
    In Separatabzug aus dem Blauen Reiter.
  - Vortrag über Kandinsky nach seinem Tode for einige Freunde / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Paris, 1944., 6 p.; 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 224)
    Typescript in German with manuscript corrections.
    1 original with 2 revisions (7 p. and 8 p.)
- Biographical Materials, Series V
  - Biographies, V.A
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 225)
      With review excerpts (2 p.) and list of works (7 p.)
      Typescript in English, photocopy.
      Manuscript annotations, 1 copy only.
      With 2 additional published copies.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 1 p.; 21 cm. (Box 25, Folder 225)
      With list of works (4 p.)
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 13 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 225)
      With French translation, (10 p.; 28 cm.)
      Unidentified author.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 226)
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 226)
      Typescript in French, photocopy.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 6 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 226)
      Typescript in German, English and French.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 226)
      Typescript in German, photocopy.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 6 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 227)
      By I. Cabonola.
      With 2 copies of newspaper article [n.d.] where it appeared.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 5 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 228)
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 4 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 228)
      Typescript in French.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 228)
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann., 4 p.; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 229)
      By Serge Moreux.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann. -- 1984., 3 p. [54-56]; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 230)
      Typescript English, French and German.
      Excerpt from a program for an exhibition at the London Regional Art Gallery about the life of Canadian tenor Henri Pontbriand.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann and Olga de Hartmann. -- 1976 Apr. 4., 1 p.; 38 cm. (Box 25, Folder 231)
      From a newspaper article in The New Mexican.
    - Biography of Thomas de Hartmann. -- 1956 Mar. 26., 1 p.; 10 cm. (Box 25, Folder 231)
      Laminated card with newspaper obituary.
    - Thomas de Hartmann: in search of an Unknown Music / Rafi Zabor. -- New York, 1981., 5 p. [p. 1, p. 8-12]; 28 cm. (Box 25, Folder 232)
      In Oak Music Report.
  - Datebooks, V.B
    - 1940-1941, 3 items. (Box 25, Folder 233)
    - 1947-1953, 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 234)
    - 1954-1956, 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 235)
  - Calendars, V.C
    - 1945-1962, 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 236)
  - Addressbooks, V.D
    - Addressbooks, 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 237)
    - Addressbooks, 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 238)
  - Small Notebooks, V.E
    - Notebooks, 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 239)
    - Notebooks, 2 items. (Box 26, Folder 240)
- Programs, Reviews and Clippings, Series VI
  - Programs, VI.A
    - 1956-1959, 7 items. (Box 26, Folder 241)
    - 1975-1983, 5 items. (Box 26, Folder 242)
    - 1987, 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 243)
    - n.d., 2 items. (Box 26, Folder 243)
  - Reviews, VI.B
    - Collected excerpts from reviews., 1935.; 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 244)
    - Collected excerpts from reviews., 1935.; 4 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 244)
      Typescript in French and English.
    - Collected excerpts from reviews., n.d.; 2 p.; 31 cm. (Box 26, Folder 244)
  - Clippings, VI.C
    - 1935-1981, 6 items. (Box 26, Folder 244)
- Photographs and Portraits, Series VII
  - Thomas de Hartmann alone, VII.A
    - Thomas de Hartmann alone., #1-4 (Box 26, Folder 245)
  - Thomas de Hartmann and Olga de Hartmann, VII.B
    - Thomas de Hartmann and Olga de Hartmann., #5-7 (Box 26, Folder 246)
  - Groups, VII.C
    - Mr. and Mrs. Franz Marc, Bernard Kohler, Heinrich Campendonck, Thomas de Hartmann (far right), Kandinsky (seated)., #8-9 (Box 26, Folder 247)
      With negative.
  - Others (Individuals), VII.D
    - Arensky, Anton, 1902 Sep. 12; #10 (Box 26, Folder 248)
    - Bauchiuv, Arte, n.d.; #11 (Box 26, Folder 248)
    - Casals, Pablo, 1947; #12 (Box 26, Folder 248)
    - Grechaninov, A., 1954; #13 (Box 26, Folder 249)
    - Noff, Gloza, n.d.; #14 (Box 26, Folder 249)
    - Tcherepnine, Nikolay, n.d.; #15 (Box 26, Folder 249)
  - Others (Groups), VII.E
    - Parents of Olga de Hartmann., 1931 May 3; #16-17 (Box 26, Folder 250)
    - Unidentified., 1931 May 3; #18-27 (Box 26, Folder 250)
      With manuscript register that appears to correspond with unidentified photos above.
    - Negatives that correspond with unidentified photos above., #28-48 (Box 26, Folder 251)
  - Places and Things, VII.F
    - Thomas de Hartmann's grave, Princeton, N.J., #49 (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - Drawing by Kandinsky (unidentified), #50 (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - Arc de Triomphe, Paris., #51 (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - Boat on water (unidentified), #52 (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - House and surrounding garden (unidentified), #53-56 (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - House (unidentified), #57 (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - Film fragments (unidentified), #58-70 (Box 26, Folder 253)
  - Portraits, VII.G
    - Small framed portraits, possibly by Elizabeth Shoumatoff., #3 (Box 26, Folder 254)
- List of Works, Series VIII
  - List of works by M. P. Belaieff., 6 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 255)
  - List of works by M. P. Belaieff., 9 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 255)
  - List of works by M. P. Belaieff., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 255)
  - List of works by C. F. Peters., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 255)
    With 7 additional photocopies of p. 1.
  - List of works., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 255)
  - List of works., 30 p.; 22 cm. (Box 26, Folder 255)
    Manuscript in pencil and ink.
- Literary Writings by Others, Series IX
  - Arabism and Peace., Allawerdi, Michael; 20 p.; 24 cm. (Box 27, Folder 256)
    Translation in Arabic.
  - In memory of Mitrofan Petrovich Bieliaev, a collection of sketches, articles, and remembrances. -- 1929., Bieliaev, Mitrofan Petrovich; 178 p.; 22 cm. (Box 27, Folder 257)
  - Das Neue Testament / German translation by Martin Luther. -- Berlin, 1876., Luther, Martin, 1483-1546; 547 p.; 13 cm. (Box 27, Folder 258)
  - Tower and town., Pichel, Irving, 1891-1954; 24 p.; 28 cm. (Box 27, Folder 259)
    Screenplay.
    Typescript, ditto copy.
    Screen adaption by S. Richard Tanin.
  - Esther, tragédie / Jean Racine. -- Paris: Louis Cellot, 1768., Racine, Jean; iv, 440 p.; 21 cm. (Box 27, Folder 260)
  - Biography, list of works, and press reviews., Tcherepnin, Alexander, 1899-1977; 4 p.; 24 cm. (Box 27, Folder 261)
    Pamphlet, typescript in English.
  - The story of the tower / Frank Lloyd Wright. -- New York: Horizon, 1956., Wright, Frank Lloyd; 134 p.; 29 cm. (Box 27, Folder 262)
    Autographed on inside cover by Frank Lloyd Wright.
  - In search of an unreachable (from a Canadian press dispatch, datelined Feb. 21, 1971), Unidentified; 2 p.; 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 263)
    Typescript. photocopy.
    At beginning: About Pete.
- Miscellaneous Items, Series X
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 28, Folder 264)
    - Business cards of Thomas de Hartmann., 9 items.
    - Calendar of musical events from the Grand Casino de Vichy, 1937., 1 item.
  - Folder with colored dividers containing names and addresses of people and publishers., 1 item. (Box 28, Folder 265)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 28, Folder 266)
    - Invitations., 3 items.
    - Piece of stationery with Thomas de Hartmann's signature with separate manuscript note., 2 items.
    - Lists of names, 1 with additional manuscript notes and floor plan of a house., 2 items.
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 28, Folder 267)
    - List of Russian words in manuscript (7 p.), 1 item.
    - Conjugation of French verbs in manuscript (2 p.), 1 item.
    - List of orchestral instruments., 1 item.
    - Miscellaneous manuscript notes., 17 items.
    - Miscellaneous fragments of paper all with manuscript notes., 5 items.
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 29)
    [contents of box 29 not in folders]
    - Leather briefcase., 1 item.
    - Plaque from Thomas de Hartmann's regiment, 1917., 1 item.
    - Société des Auteurs, Compositeurs, et Éditeurs membership plaque., 1 item.
    - Russian character stamp., 1 item.
    - Cigarette holder., 1 item.
    - Gold lyre [a present after premiere of The Pink Flower], 1 item.
    - Gold watch [originally owned by Thomas de Hartmann's father], 1 item.
    - Coptic cross., 1 item.
    - Instruments for making transparent scores., 1 item.
    - Wallets., 3 items.
    - Barometer with broken glass., 1 item.
    - Pairs of eyeglasses., 2 items.
    - Eyeglass cases., 4 items.
    - Photograph storage book [empty], 1 item.
- Items Relating to G.I. Gurdjieff, Series XI
  - Conversations with Gurdjieff (possibly an interview), 27 p.; 33 cm. (Box 30, Folder 268)
    Manuscript in Russian, photocopy.
    3 copies, 2 incomplete.
  - Epigrams (possibly by Gurdjieff)., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 30, Folder 269)
    With small manuscript note.
  - Epigrams (possibly by Gurdjieff)., 2 p.; 26 cm. (Box 30, Folder 269)
  - Inscriptions on the ceiling of the study house in Prieuré., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 30, Folder 269)
    Annotations in pen, 1 copy only.